Salim Shaikh

Email: shaikhsalim1513104@gmail.com

Mob: 9022452263

Address: Latur, Maharashtra, India

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/shaikh-salim-22506a182/

Github: https://www.github.com/leoms10

Summary

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and 1 year of experience in software engineering, web development and coding as intern. Seeking a challenging and rewarding position as an entry-level software engineer/developer. Well- versed in web development technologies including Java, C++ and JavaScript libraries and frameworks, SQL.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Trainee Software Engineer Intern

Webileapps, Hyderabad

November 2022 - February 2023

• Implemented functional programming javascript code to integrated components into modern web applications.

Developed games like 2048,api fetching and handling state and props using react-redux, Nodejs while following agile methodology, Web Components, REST Api.

MERN Stack Intern

Chefathome, Chennai

July 2022 - October 2022

• managed E-commerce project with Testing web application with different user test cases like on React, Redux and developed web app with MERN stack and MongoDB, increasing efficiency of the project by 25%.

Mobile app ui developer

Bugendaitech, india

February 2022 - May 2022

- using react native and built a mobile application interface functionalities such as navigation, navigation bar, page transitions, loading.
- Hands on experience with microsoft sql server, Analytical Functions, DML, DDL.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

Examination	Institute Pa		percentage
		year	
B.Tech(CSE)	M.S. Bidve Engineering college,Latur	2021	70.49
HSC	Rajarshi Shahu Junior Science college,Latur	2017	56.31
SSC	Jaikranti High School,Latur	2015	87.20

PROJECTS

Quote generator App

- This application developed using React.js which allows users to quickly andeasily generate quotes from a variety of sources.
- The app fetches quote from an API, process them, and display them in a user-friendly interface.
- Responsive web design using CSS.

Quiz website

• Developed and managed quiz website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. It allows users to take a quiz and then to be shown their score after completion. The quiz questions will be generated from a database and randomized each time the quiz is taken.

Sushi website

- Developed restaurant website using HTML, CSS. It Show cases the products available in Restaurant and services can be used for the Ecommerce services.taken reference from youtube javascript mastery
- Live Link: https://delightful-praline-ba6221.netlify.app/

SKILLS

Technical Skills: Html, CSS, Javascript, React, Frontend Web development technologies, Responsive Design, Java, User Interface design, API, mysql, SQL Server.

Tools: Github, Netlify, Visual Studio, MS-excel, office.

Soft Skills: Analytical and problem solving, Adaptive, quick learner, Good Communication.

Other: DBMS, Data Structure & Algorithms.